[music]
[Instructor] Cool, so we have
our character in the Scene,
and whenever we run
into one of the Obstacles,
right now he's so happy
we just missed one,
and we hit one of them, and you can
see "Game Over" pops up at the bottom.
Now we actually want
to be able to do things
when we end our game.
One of the thing's that we'll do
is we'll make
it so that the Background
stops scrolling,
and the Obstacles stop
when the game is over.
To do that we'll actually need to do
some communications between our Scripts
to be able to know when to stop
the game.
Now, in our MoveLeft Script,
how exactly are we going
to know what's happening
in our PlayerController Script?
Well, for now we'll create a variable
so that we can hold a reference
to our Script so...
specifically because our
PlayerController Script
is a class called
"PlayerController",
we actually just
call PlayerController.
Now, this is very similar
to how you would just
call GameObjects but in this case,
we're just calling
a PlayerController,
and we'll name this "player...
Controller... Script,"
and although not very creative,
is very descriptive
which is incredibly helpful.
Now, in our Start() method
this is actually
how we're going to connect
our reference to our Script
to the actual PlayerController Script
in our game. So, we're going
to use our playerControllerScript,
and we're going to set
this to the PlayerController Script
on our Player.
So we can actually use
the GameObject class,
and in our game,
we're going to Find()
the name of our Object,
which in this case in our game
is called, "Player"
so this'll find Player
in the Scene Hierarchy,
and now that we've found our Player
we can actually get their Component,
and we're looking for specifically
their "PlayerController" Object
which we put inside the left,
and right carets.
And then, since this is a method,
we make sure
that we put our parenthesis.
So now this is how we can set
our PlayerControllerScript
to be the actual PlayerController Script
in our game
by using the Player
in our scene.
And now in our Update() method,
we can actually stop things from moving
whenever we Collide with that Player,
and the gameOver condition happens.
So if()...
playerControllerScript,
since we now have that reference,
and we want to check
whenever the game is over,
however in this case we're looking
to move things
when the game is not over so,
if gameOver
is equal to false
we use those two equal signs
to say that it's equal to
instead of setting
gameOver to false,
and then we use our curly brackets,
and then press Enter,
and we can actually just cut
this entire translate() method,
and put it inside
this if() statement.
One very important thing to note
is that you can see
that we can very easily
get our gameOver variable
from our PlayerControllerScript.
Now, if this was
a private variable,
in fact we wouldn't be able
to see this at all.
Now, if gameOver
were a private variable,
we wouldn't be able
to see this at all.
Just like public variables can
be seen in the Unity Editor,
and private variables cannot,
public variables can be seen
in other classes
while private variables cannot.
So if I were to get
a MoveLeft Script somewhere,
and I wanted to get
the speed variable
I would have no way
of doing that.
If I made the gameOver
variable private
inside of our PlayerController Script,
I would have no way
of seeing this variable,
and being able to know
if it was true or false.
So now,
if our gameOver is false,
if our game is not over,
then we're just going to keep moving
things to the left.
So if we save in Unity,
now this time when we Play the game,
and our Player runs
into one of the Obstacles,
everything stops.
And we're still jumping
for joy, so excited,
and you can see
all of these Obstacles,
just Spawning on each other,
and there's not enough space.
Now what you're going to do
is in your MoveLeft Script,
you're going to get a reference
of our playerControllerScript
on our Player
by creating your own
PlayerController variable.
In our Start() method,
you're going to set that variable
to the PlayerController Object
or Component
on our Player GameObject
in our scene,
and then whenever the game
is not over
we're going to make sure
that all of our Obstacles,
and our Background keeps moving
until our Game Over happens.
Now it's your turn.
[music]